Jonathon Carrasco

ECONOMIST · DATA SCIENTIST

5425 Verdome Ln, Houston, TX 77092

□ (713) 301-2050 | Signorarrasco@outlook.com | A joncarrasco.com | DonathonCarrasco | Mojonshine

Summary ____

I have 15 years of experience of working with data in finance, commercial real estate, and medicine. Each of these fields have exposed me to a diverse set of statistical and econometric tools that I draw upon to tackle any question. It doesn't matter if you are working with millions of observations or a small curated sample, data requires a compelling story that can told with clarity to be meaningful. Data wrangling can be messy but with the help of scripts and APIs it is possible to stitch together datasets from disparate sources for reliable analysis on demand. I am also familiar with programs like ArcGIS and Tableau for geoprocessing data for map creation and spatial analysis. Beyond these technical skills, I have studied commodity markets, fixed income securities, and financial derivatives which allow me a more complete perspective of financial markets in general.

Education

University of Houston

Houston, TX

M.A. IN ECONOMICS

August 2013 - May 2016

University of Houston

Houston, TX

M.S. IN FINANCE

August 2008 - December 2013

Rice University

B.A. IN MATHEMATICAL ECONOMIC ANALYSIS WITH HONORS

Houston, TX

August 2002 - May 2006

Professional Experience.

CBRE Houston, TX

DATA INTELLIGENCE ANALYST

September 2016 - Present

Data Visualization

Dashboards that I have built in Tableau and R have been featured by CBRE Research as a Global Best Practice. I have been invited on multiple occasions to teach advanced Tableau training sessions to my research peers across the company. My interactive portfolios, maps, and skylines have been featured in point of sale presentations and pitches in the office, retail, and multifamily lines of business. My most recent piece is a quarterly Office and Industrial Market Share dashboard that is being adopted by the Managing Directors of the South-Central Region.

Data Management

Under my leadership, the Digital Intelligence team has improved the quantity and quality of our proprietary database of lease comps and property data. Custom scripts that I have written in Python and Excel now allow our team to capture internal comp information in half the time and deliver an on-the-fly customized report to both brokers and management. My efforts to standardize and automate data collection by scraping websites and utilizing APIs allows the research team to circulate market reports and present economic data each quarter without production lag.

Point of Sale

I have been invited to share my data visualizations and analysis in client briefings and at the point of sale in both Agency and Occupier pitches. By working alongside the brokers, I ensure that the analysis I present is tailored to the question at hand and in step with the overall vision the team is advocating. Because of my background in economics I have been called on to speak with authority on broader market trends and macroeconomic indicators. I am currently responsible for delivering a quarterly overview on the Houston economy and office market in the Office, Industrial, and Debt and Structured Finance lines of business meetings.

FEBRUARY 5, 2019 1

Lone Star College Cypress, TX

ADJUNCT PROFESSOR January 2014 - Present

I currently teach three hour introductory Microeconomic and Macroeconomic classes in both a face-to-face and online setting. I am responsible for constructing a course syllabus, writing exams, and maintaining an online classroom complete with discussion boards and weekly assignments to supplement coursework. Courses taught are credit bearing and the college is regionally accredited.

University of Houston Houston, TX

RESEARCH AND TEACHING ASSISTANT

August 2008 - May 2013

Extensive experience in data collection, management, and econometric analysis for academic research and publication. Also responsible for teaching and grading undergraduate and MBA graduate courses at the University of Houston. Received the Clay and Lucy Carter Teaching Excellence Award.

The Methodist Hospital

Houston, TX

RESEARCH FELLOW May 2005 - July 2008

Fellowship to study how patients make medical decisions under severe uncertainty. Developed mathematical models to use biometric data and help patients discover their personal normals and provide feedback to manage chronic disease. Awarded a fellowship to apply six-sigma principles to study blood bank procedures and develop more robust methods. Produced "In Context" a biweekly podcast with Dr. Clifford Dacso on current medical news. Published a peer reviewed article on uncertainty in medicine and presented research at conferences in the US and abroad.

Technical Skills

Programming Python • Matlab • R • Stata • ArcGIS • ŁTFX • Excel Macros and Pivot Tables • SQL • HTML & CSS

Statistical Expertise

Linear Regressions • Maximum Likelihood Estimation • Logit & Probit Models • ARIMA Models with Trend • GARCH Models • Bayesian Analysis • Unit Root Testing • Markov Chain Monte Carlo Simulation • Identification of Structural Breaks • Regression Discontinuities • Spectral Analysis • Jackknife & Bootstrap Resampling • Sample Size & Power

Calculations

Selected Coursework

Economics

Macroeconomic Modeling & Forecasting • Applied Econometrics • Urban Economics • DSGE Models • Monetary Policy • International Monetary Economics

Finance

Options & Futures • Fixed Income Securities • Continuous Time Finance • Financial Management • Financial Econometrics • International Finance & Macroeconomics

Honors & Awards

2009	Clay & Lucy Carter Teaching Excellence Award, C.T. Bauer College of Business, University of Houston	Houston, TX
2008	Dyer Fellowship for Improving Patient Care Through Research, The Methodist Hospital	Houston, TX
2006	Philpott Award for Service to Baker College and Rice University, Rice University	Houston, TX
2005	Finger Fellowship for Sustainable Health, The Methodist Hospital	Houston, TX
2002	Barbara Jordan Scholar, Rice University	Houston, TX

FEBRUARY 5, 2019